#### **MUTHU PALANIAPPAN**

Mobile: +6597830236, E-mail: plmuthu.arch07@gmail.com



#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

I am a passionate architect with five and half years working experience. Graduated from M.S.C in Building performance and Sustainability from National University of Singapore (NUS) and Bachelors of Architecture from Thiagarajar College of Engineering, Anna University. The knowledge from ISD course have enhanced my understanding of passive building design, its concepts and equipped me with the capability to demonstrate sustainable development concepts and theories. My experience has shaped my strength in conceptual design, construction drawing, sustainable building systems, verbal & graphical communication, handling clients and working with other professionals. I am a hardworking and driven person, with exceptional leadership quality and an in-depth understanding of all phases of building design process, from inception to completion.

My passion for architecture and learning, strives me constantly to improve my skills and understanding. With these set of skills and competence, combined with my working experience in variety of projects I intend to bring forth new creative and strategic design ideas

#### **EDUCATION**

National University of Singapore, Singapore

August 2012-May 2013

Master of Science in Integrated Sustainable Design, MSc

Thiagarajar college of Engineering, Madurai, India Affiliated to Anna University Bachelor of Architecture, BArch August 2003-May 2008

# RESEARCH

Student Research Assistant for Centre for Sustainable Asian Cities (CSAC) on the topic **Urban space** planning for sustainable high density environments

# SKILLS AND PROFICIENCIES

REVIT, AutoCAD 2015, Sketch-up, InDesign, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Basics of 3D Max & Ecotect

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **CPG CONSULTANTS – AIRPORT DIVISION | Singapore**

Aug 2013 - Present

CPG Consultants is a multiple award-winning architectural practice based in Singapore and works on a diverse range of projects including residential, industrial, institutional, master planning, mixed-use developments and urban design. I was working with the Airport division in the firm.

I have worked in the capacity of an Architect to produce concept plans and details for small scale Vietnam airport projects. Prepared presentations for clients at every stage of design, schedules, interior finishes and feature designs. Worked in coordination with M&E and Structural consultants to deliver Construction Details and Drawings in REVIT. Gained extensive knowledge on International & Singapore standards as well on Airport planning. Was able to work along with senior Architects on large scale airport projects to produce detailed drawings that included façade details, roof details and interior details for airports.

# Notable projects

- Yangon International and Domestic Airport Development, Myanmar
- Danang Airport Development, Vietnam
- Bandaranayake International Airport, Srilanka
- Bole International Airport, Ethopia

# COS CONSULTANCY SERVICES | Madurai, India

Sep 2011-May 2012

Cos consultancy is an engineering firm in Madurai. I was recruited mainly to handle institutional and hospital projects that were major works at that time. I was entrusted with the responsibility to design and manage a team cad technicians and engineers for these projects

As Architectural lead my role is to coordinate with CAD technicians, consultants and contractors for an institutional and multi- specialty hospital projects, gained extensive experience working with large development teams, local building officials, engineers and client group in coordination of services and facilities from the inception of the project to its final stages to completion.

- Prepare /Assist in concept design and design development and produce detailed drawings
- Coordinate with teams within the company to ensure integrated approach for design.
- Coordinate with structural, MEP and relevant consultants and check for accuracy and adequacy.
- Review the tender drawings and assist the Project Manager in preparation of BOQ and specifications.
- Make regular site visits and resolve any design related issues at site.
- Approval of finishes samples and mock-ups.
- Coordinate with client & contractors to carry out work in accordance to design intent.
- Maintain documentation of all drawings and records.
- Updating senior management of all the developments / status and alert for any foreseeable issues.

#### Notable projects

- Dhaya College of Engineering, Madurai (completed): 16 acres | Architectural + Interiors
- Apollo Multi-specialty Hospital, Trichy (completed): 9.7 acres | Detail + Site coordination

# NATRAJ AND VENKAT ASSOCIATES - MHETRAS DESIGN | Chennai, India

June 2009-Sep 2010

Oct 2010-Aug 2011

NVA, a multiple award winning firm, is currently one of the largest and oldest architectural practices Based in Chennai since 1969, the Firm's range of projects includes buildings for IT Parks, Residential and Office Campuses. Mhetras Design was led by one of the chief architect of NVA conceptualizing in commercial range such as Theaters, Large Club houses and Luxury residential development.

Managed multiple residential and Office complex from design conceptualization stage to preparing construction documents and site visits. Effectively led a team of one Junior Architect and two CAD Technicians to develop produce and deliver construction documents. Collaborated with senior client decision- makers to develop requirements. Created detailed drawings, specifications, resource estimates and timetables. Other responsibilities included,

- Maintain regular communication with client.
- Solicited bids, negotiated and administered vendor contracts
- Coordinate with site engineers to ensure that construction is carried out as per drawings.
- Coordinate with structural, MEP, sanitary and relevant consultants.
- Make site visits as and when necessary.
- Maintain documentation of all drawings and records.

#### Notable projects

- Multi-storey Residential Neighborhood (Lancor, Arihanth), Chennai (completed): Construction set drawings and site coordination
- Arihant Corporate Office Building and Apartments, Chennai (completed): 11,000 sqft | Developed plan, site layout and prepared construction set drawings
- Papalaguda and Raheja Township projects, Hyderabad: Prepared concepts along with Senior Designer and produced presentation drawings for clients meetings
- Multiplex and IMAX Theatre, Chennai, (proposed): Theater | Proposal for IMAX + Multi-storey Car parking concept design.
- Developed details and presentations in co-ordination with CPG Architects, Singapore on renovation of theatre complex interiors for Satyam Theaters

# **INTERNSHIP**

# CREATIVE ARCHITECTS AND INTERIORS | Chennai, India

June 2008- May 2009

Creative Architects is a multiple award-winning Architectural practice based in Chennai and they specialize in residential and institutional buildings. There also do quite a few interior works for major banks in Chennai and Tamilnadu.

My role is to develop concept design and detailed drawings for residential and interior projects. Also Prepared working set drawings, specifications and construction documents for large scale residential projects. Contacted vendors for material samples to create mock-ups and 3-D material boards for Senior Designers

- Ashok Rathi's residence cum Office, Chennai (completed): Luxury residence | Architectural-Interiors
- Rural Training Centre, Karaikudi : Competition entry | Responsible Architecture
- Indian Overseas Bank Interiors, Chennai: Design and Develop Interior concepts
- Kesariya Housing + Medhavakkam flats, Chennai : Detailed drawings for construction

#### **OWN WORKS** | India

- Successfully designed residential and office projects based on passive design strategies. Maximized
  the use of day lighting & natural ventilation and oriented the spaces within the building considering
  the effects of solar radiation on the facades of the building. Coordinated with Structural and M&E
  consultants for preparing detailed drawing and organized site meetings until project completion.
- Publications for "THE HINDU" newspaper on topics of Environmental awareness and Architecture

#### **INTERESTS**

LEED Principles, Team leadership, Comprehensive planning, Sustainable design, Interior Design and Detailing, Painting and Photography

#### AWARDS AND WORKSHOPS

- IGBC Design of Zero Energy Building on principles of Bamboo technology- awarded special mention
- Participated in National level competition PULSE '06, Mumbai and won the Citation for the most prestigious LOUIS KHAN Trophy as a group for the documentation of Brahmin settlement in Kallidaikuruchi, Ambasamuthram District
- Best Outgoing student of the department First class with Distinction and stood on the top 3 of the class
- Herbert Dreiseitl workshop on Urban Studies and sustainable design principles
- Robert and Brenda Vale Workshop on Sustainability models and blueprints, '12
- Workshop on Building construction techniques '07
- Participated in TADO ANDO lecture on "ASIA ON THE MOVE". '13
- Documentation of chettinad residence as part of conservation works by DHAN Foundation
- ASIAN painting competition awarded first place for egg shell painting
- AKRITA '05 Competition awarded first place for abstract painting concept women's joys and sorrows

#### **AFFILIATIONS**

Member of Council of architecture (Governing body for Architects in India) Member of Indian Institute of Architects

#### CO CURRICULAR ACHIEVEMENTS

### Member, Entrepreneurship society (NUS)

August 2012- June 2013

Led a group of 4 members to assist students at NUS in getting internship.

Encouraged club members to communicate with sponsor companies which successfully increased the number of sponsors for the club's activities.

Volunteer-Exchange program activities at NUS

#### PERSONAL PARTICULARS

DOB : Febrary, 7th 1986

Marital Status : Married

Address : 1 Gateway Drive, Westgate Tower, CPG Consultants (Airport), #21-01, Sg - 415941

Email id : plmuthu.arch07@gmail.com

Contact no. : +6598693971 / +6597830236

Nationality : Indian

Sex : Female

Visa status : Employment Pass in Singapore

Availability : Upon one month notice